ALEX V. NORR

December 2014

norr2@illinois.edu 801-710-5414

#### **Education**

Master of Arts Urban and Regional Planning w/ Specialization in Real Estate University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign expected 2015

Bachelor of Science Geography: Urban and Environmental Planning Brigham Young University 2013

# **Areas of Expertise**

Real Estate
Market Analysis
Transportation Planning
Land Use Planning
Economic Development
Site Planning

#### **Technical Skills**

ARGUS IMPLAN Cube-6 ArcGIS

Adobe Creative Suite Microsoft Office

### **Professional References**

## Andrew K. Jackson, AICP

Executive Director Mountainland Association of Governments (801) 367-0699

#### **Greg Haws**

Senior Project Manager / Planner Psomas (801) 755-8016

## **Brandon Stocksdale**

Long Range Planner Orem City, UT (801) 229-7055

# **Professional Summary**

Alex will complete his graduate degree of Urban Planning in May 2015. As part of his graduate education he also obtained a specialization in Real Estate provided through the Illinois College of Business, Department of Finance, at the University of Illinois Urbana Champaign. He currently works with the University of Illinois Extension conducting local and regional economic impact analysis. During his first year of graduate school Alex established Practik Urban Planning Solutions, a private planning consulting firm, where he continues to seek and complete contracts as time allows.

# **Relevant Work Experience**

**University of Illinois Extension Intern, 2014, Champaign, IL**—Project leader for the 2014 IAAF Economic Impact Study of county fairs and Disaster Response Plan for Extension facilities and events.

**Teaching Assistant, 2013-2014, UIUC, IL**—Facilitated section labs on urban economics and basic planning principles in the department of Urban and Regional Planning.

Consultant, Practik Urban Planning Solutions, 2013-Present, SLC, UT—Consultant for Initiating Wendover City General Plan update, and integration planning for Wellsville City Envision Utah plan.

**Genola Comprehensive Plan, 2012, Genola, UT**—Intern planner in developing the general plan.

Transportation and Land Use Model Development, 2012, Provo, UT—Research lead, worked with local elected officials and planners in the design and development of integrated transportation and land use models for Guam, Hawaii, and Puerto Rico.

# **Relevant Course Work**

Real Estate Valuation; Real Estate Economics; Real Estate Development; Landuse Law; Urban and Regional Analysis; Economic Modeling; Plan Making

# Relevant Leadership Experience

- Vice President, Rho Epsilon—University of Illinois 2014-Present
- USAF, Reserve Officer Training Core—DET 855, Provo UT, 2010-2013
- President, Student Urban Planning Association—BYU, 2012
- BYU Student Advisory Council—BYU, 2011-2012
- President, BYU College Council—BYU FHSS, 2012-2013